Álvaro Parra Pascual /

Partner

Practice Area: Tax Law

alvaro.parra@ocl.cl

Alvaro is a founding partner in charge of the Tax area. He has a broad strategic vision and complete understanding of tax issues and business development in general because of his sound academic formation, professional and academic experience. He is an expert in structuring businesses and investment projects, both national and international, taking into special account tax impacts and taxpayer compliance.

WORK HISTORY

2017 - present / Ovalle Consejeros Legales

2016 - 2017 / Deloitte Tax & Legal - Senior Manager

2009 - 2016 / Ovalle y Compañía Limitada

EXPERIENCE

- Taxation and investment structure in the purchase of Chilean telecommunications, electricity and unconventional energy companies by foreign entities.
- Taxation and structuring of investments outside of Chile.
- Counsel in local investment projects, analysis of different compliance and taxation matters.

EDUCATION

S.J.D (c), International Taxation, University of Florida.

LL.M., International Taxation, University of Florida, 2011.

B.A. in Legal and Social Sciences, Pontifical Catholic University of Chile. Admissions: 2009.

ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

- Professor of Non-Resident Taxation, Universidad Mayor.
- Aid in the Tax Law Course, Pontifical Catholic University of Chile.

PUBLICATIONS

Parra Pascual, A. "New transfer pricing regulations: A practical analysis in light of U.S. Law." Tax Law Almanac, Diego Portales University. Year IV, #4. Santiago, Chile (December 2012).

Parra Pascual, A. & Vakhtinskaya, E.M. "Beyond the smoke: an alternative way to determine the excise duty rate." Nalogovyi vestnik (Tax Bulletin) #6, pp. 104–109. Moscow, Russia (2012) http://www.nalvest.com/nv-books/detail. php?ID=39050

Parra Pascual, A. & Vakhtinskaya, E.M. "Procedural peculiarities of consideration of tax disputes in Australia and the United States." Nalogi (Taxes) Magazine Five, pp. 36 - 40. Moscow, Russia (2011).

MEMBERSHIPS

- International Fiscal Association (IFA), Chile Branch
- Chilean Bar Association

LANGUAGES

Spanish and English